

Madani Djamel

Address:

Tizi-Ouzou Algeria

Phone:

+213 (0)559733551

Email:

djamelmadani15@gmail.com

LinkedIn: Madani Djamel

GitHub: Djamel96

Skill Highlights

- Scrum IT project management
- Mobile & web developer
- Information system designer
- IT trainer
- Entrepreneur

Programming

C, PHP OOP, HTML, CSS, Dart, Flutter, Laravel, JavaScript, Node.js, Vue.js, jQuery, Python, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Oracle, SQLite, MariaDB

Languages

• Kabyle: mother tongue

English: speak and write

French: speak and write

Arab: speak and write

Tools

MS Project, Android Studio, VScode, Google suite, SharePoint, PowToon, Git & GitHub, Microsoft office, Linux, Latex

Hobbies

Entrepreneurship, volunteering, Training, Sports, Travels, psychology, Novels, Hackathons, Mathematics, History, general culture, Competitions

Summary

Information systems engineer, senior Mobile Developer specializing in iOS & Android development. Junior back end developer. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic mobile projects. Functional specifications designer of development projects. Currently, co-founder of the startup IpsumIT specialized in IT development

Experience

- Information system designer since 2018
- Business process modeling with BPMN
- Modeling of technical processes with UML
- Relational and no-Relational database designer
- Free-lance: 2017 until now
- Mobile & web developer: 2017 until now
- Firebase and pusher integration for reel time applications
- E-payment integration with Stripe
- Mobile development and code versioning trainer since 2019
- Cooperate with designers to create clean interfaces, simple and intuitive interactions and experiences.
- Writing detailed functional specifications
- Develop project concepts and maintain optimal workflow.
- Work with senior developer to manage large and complex design projects for corporate clients.
- Electronic document management EDM with SharePoint
- Carry out quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability.
- Creation of a startup named Makelti specializing in the digitization of catering in companies and universities in 2019 until now

Volunteer work

- Active member in scientific clubs (CSE, ETIC & CVE)
- Training session in mobile and web development for students
- Introduction to algorithms sessions for high school students
- Conferences to orientate new bachelors towards university specialties
- Organizer of 'Village cleaning' every weekend
- Organizing member in several hackathons
- IT coach in several programming and startup creation competitions
- Free IT consulting for new startups in need
- Free website development for humanitarian associations

Education and courses

- 2015: Mathematic Baccalaureate diploma with honors
- 2015-2020: higher studies for obtaining a computer engineer diploma at the high national school of computer science, ESI ex INI Algiers
- 2020: year-round practical internship at Incubme
- Coursera Business English Communication Skills specialization 2020
- Coursera PHP development course 2018
- Coursera Google Cloud Computing course 2020
- Udacity Full stack web development course 2018
- Udacity Mobile development course 2019
- Udacity Data analytics course 2018
- Udacity Introduction to psychology course 2017
- Udemy Flutter development course 2018
- Lynda IT fundamentals and advanced pack of courses (16 courses) 2017

Certificates

PHP development Coursera, Project management MS Project Full stack web developer Udacity, Cisco Networking & Security Fundamentals Android development Udacity, INJAZ Entrepreneurship Participation Certificate, Elip Entrepreneurship training and competition Certificate